[{"subject": null, "Question": "Literature on Cardiac amyloidosis.  Please let me know where I can get literature on Cardiac amyloidosis.  My uncle died yesterday from this disorder.  Since this is such a rare disorder, and to honor his memory, I would like to distribute literature at his funeral service.  I am a retired NIH employee, so I am familiar with the campus in case you have literature at NIH that I can come and pick up.  Thank you ", "focus": "cardiac amyloidosis", "type": "information", "Answer": "Cardiac amyloidosis is a disorder caused by deposits of an abnormal protein (amyloid) in the heart tissue. These deposits make it hard for the heart to work properly."}, {"subject": "treatment options versus migraine types", "Question": "Migraine seems to be a spectrum of conditions rather than only one easily diagnosed affliction.  Many innovative migraine treatments are now in use, but it seems that each treatment only addresses a narrow set of conditions; for example, my daughter has tried many different treatment options (QEEG, HEG, TMS, topamax, ...) without success.  Has any research been done to characterize which treatment types are effective against which migraine types?", "focus": "migraine", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "There is no specific cure for migraine headaches. The goal is to treat your migraine symptoms right away, and to prevent symptoms by avoiding or changing your triggers.   A key step is learning how to manage your migraines at home. A headache diary can help you identify your headache triggers. Then you and your doctor can plan how to avoid these triggers.  If you have frequent migraines, your doctor may prescribe medicine to reduce the number of attacks. You need to take the medicine every day for it to be effective. Medicines may include:  - Antidepressants  - Blood pressure medicines  - Seizure medicines    Botulinum toxin type A (Botox) injections may also help reduce migraine attacks if they occur more than 15 days a month.  Some people find relief with minerals and vitamins. Check with your doctor to see if riboflavin or magnesium are right for you.  TREATING AN ATTACK  Other medicines are taken at the first sign of a migraine attack. Over-the-counter (OTC) pain medicines, such as acetaminophen, ibuprofen, or aspirin are often helpful when your migraine is mild. Be aware that:   - Taking medicines more than 3 days a week may lead to rebound headaches. These are headaches that keep coming back due to overuse of pain medicine.  - Taking too much acetaminophen can damage your liver.  - Too much ibuprofen or aspirin can irritate your stomach or kidneys.    If these treatments do not help, ask your doctor about prescription medicines. These include nasal sprays, suppositories, or injections.   Some migraine medicines narrow the blood vessels. If you are at risk for having a heart attack or have heart disease, talk with your doctor before using these medicines. Some migraine medicines should not be used by pregnant women. Talk with your doctor about which medicine is right for you if you are pregnant or planning to become pregnant.  Other medicines treat symptoms of migraine, such as nausea and vomiting. They may be used alone or along with the other drugs that treat the migraine itself.   Feverfew is a herb for migraines. It can be effective for some people. Before using feverfew, make sure your doctor approves. Herbal remedies sold in drugstores and health food stores are not regulated. Work with a trained herbalist when selecting herbs."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "DO I USE PYRIDOXINE TABLETS EVEN IF IM PREGNANT?", "focus": "pyridoxine", "type": "contraindication", "Answer": "Before taking pyridoxine,        tell your doctor and pharmacist if you are allergic to pyridoxine or any other drugs.      tell your doctor and pharmacist what prescription and nonprescription medications you are taking, especially levodopa (Larodopa, Sinemet), phenobarbital, phenytoin (Dilantin), and other vitamins.      tell your doctor if you are pregnant, plan to become pregnant, or are breast-feeding. If you become pregnant while taking pyridoxine, call your doctor."}, {"subject": "cramp", "Question": "i have lymphoma what causes cramp after chemo treatment", "focus": "cramp", "type": "cause", "Answer": "Muscle cramps are common and often occur when a muscle is overused or injured. Working out when you have not had enough fluids (dehydration) or when you have low levels of minerals such as potassium or calcium can also make you more likely to have a muscle spasm.  Muscle cramps can occur while you play tennis or golf, bowl, swim, or do any other exercise.   They can also be triggered by:  - Alcoholism  - Hypothyroidism (underactive thyroid)  - Kidney failure  - Medications  - Menstruation  - Pregnancy"}, {"subject": "Retina", "Question": "I wonder of new research and testing on macular degeneration and the opportunity to be part of this process.", "focus": "macular degeneration", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "These resources address the diagnosis or management of age-related macular degeneration:  - BrightFocus Foundation: Macular Degeneration Treatment  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 1  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 10  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 11  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 2  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 3  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 4  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 7  - Genetic Testing Registry: Age-related macular degeneration 9  - Genetic Testing Registry: Susceptibility to age-related macular degeneration, wet type  - Genetic Testing Registry: Susceptibility to neovascular type of age-related macular degeneration  - Macular Degeneration Partnership: Low Vision Rehabilitation  - Prevent Blindness America: Age-Related Macular Degeneration (AMD) Test - Amsler Grid   These resources from MedlinePlus offer information about the diagnosis and management of various health conditions:  - Diagnostic Tests  - Drug Therapy  - Surgery and Rehabilitation  - Genetic Counseling   - Palliative Care"}, {"subject": "hypothyroidism", "Question": "Can you please send me as much information as possible on &quot;hypothyroidism&quot;. I was recently diagnosed with the disease and I am struggling to figure out what it is and how I got it. My name and address is: [NAME] [LOCATION] [CONTACT] Thank you in advance for your help!!!", "focus": "hypothyroidism", "type": "information", "Answer": "Hypothyroidism is a condition in which the thyroid gland does not make enough thyroid hormone. This condition is often called underactive thyroid."}, {"subject": "help about rabbies", "Question": "A street dog bit me five years ago, I take all the vaccine from very next day from biting, now on that spot where bite there was etching problem since few day, please guide me is there any problem will create in future if create is there any treatment for rabies.", "focus": "rabies", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Clean the wound well with soap and water, and seek professional medical help. You will need a doctor to thoroughly clean the wound and remove any foreign objects. Most of the time, stitches should not be used for animal bite wounds.  If there is any risk of rabies, you will be given a series of a preventive vaccine. The vaccine is generally given in 5 doses over 28 days.  Most patients also receive a treatment called human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG). This treatment\u00a0is given the day the bite occurred.  Call your doctor right away after an animal bite or after being exposed to animals such as bats, foxes, and skunks. They may carry rabies.  - Call even when no bite took place.  - Immunization and treatment for possible rabies are recommended for at least up to 14 days after exposure or a bite.    There is no known effective treatment for people with symptoms of a rabies infection, but there have been a few reports of people surviving with experimental treatments."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "Dear Sir/Madam  I'm [NAME] from [LOCATION], I'm 35 years old , I'd like to ask you a\u00a0Medical Question as I've got an optic nerve atrophy in my eye and i lost my vision since i was 8 years old , Now I've got one eye just ,  So please is there treatment for optic nerve atrophy !  Please see the attachment which is a Medical report from [LOCATION],  Best Wishes  [NAME] ", "focus": "optic nerve atrophy", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Damage from optic nerve atrophy cannot be reversed. The underlying disease must be found and treated. Otherwise, vision loss will continue.   Rarely, conditions that lead to optic atrophy may be treatable."}, {"subject": "Night Blindness", "Question": "When and how do you know when you have congenital night blindness?", "focus": "congenital night blindness", "type": "symptom", "Answer": "X-linked congenital stationary night blindness is a disorder of the retina, which is the specialized tissue at the back of the eye that detects light and color. People with this condition typically have difficulty seeing in low light (night blindness). They also have other vision problems, including loss of sharpness (reduced acuity), severe nearsightedness (high myopia), involuntary movements of the eyes (nystagmus), and eyes that do not look in the same direction (strabismus). Color vision is typically not affected by this disorder. The vision problems associated with this condition are congenital, which means they are present from birth. They tend to remain stable (stationary) over time. Researchers have identified two major types of X-linked congenital stationary night blindness: the complete form and the incomplete form. The types have very similar signs and symptoms. However, everyone with the complete form has night blindness, while not all people with the incomplete form have night blindness. The types are distinguished by their genetic cause and by the results of a test called an electroretinogram, which measures the function of the retina.\n"}, {"subject": null, "Question": "Would appreciate any good info on Lewy Body Dementia, we need to get people aware of this dreadful disease, all they talk about is alzheimers.  Thank you ", "focus": "lewy body dementia", "type": "information", "Answer": "Summary       Lewy body disease is one of the most common causes of dementia in the elderly. Dementia is the loss of mental functions severe enough to affect normal activities and relationships. Lewy body disease happens when abnormal structures, called Lewy bodies, build up in areas of the brain. The disease may cause a wide range of symptoms, including       - Changes in alertness and attention    - Hallucinations    - Problems with movement and posture    - Muscle stiffness    - Confusion    - Loss of memory       Lewy body disease can be hard to diagnose, because Parkinson's disease and Alzheimer's disease cause similar symptoms. Scientists think that Lewy body disease might be related to these diseases, or that they sometimes happen together.    Lewy body disease usually begins between the ages of 50 and 85. The disease gets worse over time. There is no cure. Treatment focuses on drugs to help symptoms.     NIH: National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke"}, {"subject": "Maple Syrup Urine Disease", "Question": "Gene changes or chromosomal changes of MSUD? What is the technical and simple language of MSUD? Are there any treatments for MSUD?", "focus": "maple syrup urine disease", "type": "genetic changes", "Answer": "Mutations in the BCKDHA, BCKDHB, and DBT genes can cause maple syrup urine disease. These three genes provide instructions for making proteins that work together as a complex. The protein complex is essential for breaking down the amino acids leucine, isoleucine, and valine, which are present in many kinds of food, particularly protein-rich foods such as milk, meat, and eggs.    Mutations in any of these three genes reduce or eliminate the function of the protein complex, preventing the normal breakdown of leucine, isoleucine, and valine. As a result, these amino acids and their byproducts build up in the body. Because high levels of these substances are toxic to the brain and other organs, their accumulation leads to the serious health problems associated with maple syrup urine disease."}, {"subject": "congenital diaphragmatic hernia", "Question": "I need to know if CDH can be passed down to future generations.  I just learned that this condition most likely caused the death of my first child back in 1971.  I was then told it was merely a fluke.  I had NO trauma during the full-term pregnancy, and I and my then husband were in very good health.  Now my son (from a different husband) and his wife are due to have fraternal twins in [DATE] 2015.  Does the term 'congenital' mean that it could be passed down to another generation?  I do not want to alarm my son and his wife.  I just would like to inform whatever pediatrician is caring for these babies as to my experience.  Unfortunately my son and I are estranged.  And I do not know who is their pediatrician.  My child's CDH was very severe.  I know there are far less severe cases that can go undetected &/or undiagnosed unless there is a reason to suspect such a condition.  Please respond to my concerns.", "focus": "cdh", "type": "inheritance", "Answer": "Isolated congenital diaphragmatic hernia is rarely inherited. In almost all cases, there is only one affected individual in a family.  When congenital diaphragmatic hernia occurs as a feature of a genetic syndrome or chromosomal abnormality, it may cluster in families according to the inheritance pattern for that condition."}, {"subject": "about thalassemia treatment", "Question": "sir,my friend is suffering from thalassemia ,in that majorly red blood anemia,white blood anemia and the blood is comming out from mouth when she got cough .her condition is very severe .in her body the red ,white blood cells are abscent .so that blood transfusion is doing for every 16-20days.then in the recent days the blood also comming out from mouth please tell me where can i get the treatment for this disease .we can travel around the world for treatment please reply me as soon as possible. thank you sir.", "focus": "thalassemia", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Treatment for thalassemia major often involves regular blood transfusions and folate supplements.  If you receive blood transfusions, you should not take iron supplements. Doing so can cause a high amount of iron to build up in the body, which can be harmful.  Persons who receive a lot of blood transfusions need a treatment called chelation therapy. This is done to remove excess iron from the body.  A bone marrow transplant may help treat the disease in some patients, especially children."}, {"subject": "insomnia", "Question": "What can I give my [AGE] father to help him sleep? He said he will take whatever. He is not on any medication, not allergic to anything.  Fully ambilatory!", "focus": "insomnia", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Lifestyle changes often can help relieve acute (short-term) insomnia. These changes might make it easier to fall asleep and stay asleep.                  A type of counseling called cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT) can help relieve the anxiety linked to chronic (ongoing) insomnia. Anxiety tends to prolong insomnia.                  Several medicines also can help relieve insomnia and re-establish a regular sleep schedule. However, if your insomnia is the symptom or side effect of another problem, it's important to treat the underlying cause (if possible).                  Lifestyle Changes                  If you have insomnia, avoid substances that make it worse, such as:                  Caffeine, tobacco, and other stimulants. The effects of these substances can last as long as 8 hours.                  Certain over-the-counter and prescription medicines that can disrupt sleep (for example, some cold and allergy medicines). Talk with your doctor about which medicines won't disrupt your sleep.                  Alcohol. An alcoholic drink before bedtime might make it easier for you to fall asleep. However, alcohol triggers sleep that tends to be lighter than normal. This makes it more likely that you will wake up during the night.                  Try to adopt bedtime habits that make it easier to fall asleep and stay asleep. Follow a routine that helps you wind down and relax before bed. For example, read a book, listen to soothing music, or take a hot bath.                  Try to schedule your daily exercise at least 5 to 6 hours before going to bed. Don't eat heavy meals or drink a lot before bedtime.                  Make your bedroom sleep-friendly. Avoid bright lighting while winding down. Try to limit possible distractions, such as a TV, computer, or pet. Make sure the temperature of your bedroom is cool and comfortable. Your bedroom also should be dark and quiet.                  Go to sleep around the same time each night and wake up around the same time each morning, even on weekends. If you can, avoid night shifts, alternating schedules, or other things that may disrupt your sleep schedule.                  Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy                  CBT for insomnia targets the thoughts and actions that can disrupt sleep. This therapy encourages good sleep habits and uses several methods to relieve sleep anxiety.                  For example, relaxation techniques and biofeedback are used to reduce anxiety. These strategies help you better control your breathing, heart rate, muscles, and mood.                  CBT also aims to replace sleep anxiety with more positive thinking that links being in bed with being asleep. This method also teaches you what to do if you're unable to fall asleep within a reasonable time.                  CBT also may involve talking with a therapist one-on-one or in group sessions to help you consider your thoughts and feelings about sleep. This method may encourage you to describe thoughts racing through your mind in terms of how they look, feel, and sound. The goal is for your mind to settle down and stop racing.                  CBT also focuses on limiting the time you spend in bed while awake. This method involves setting a sleep schedule. At first, you will limit your total time in bed to the typical short length of time you're usually asleep.                  This schedule might make you even more tired because some of the allotted time in bed will be taken up by problems falling asleep. However, the resulting tiredness is intended to help you get to sleep more quickly. Over time, the length of time spent in bed is increased until you get a full night of sleep.                  For success with CBT, you may need to see a therapist who is skilled in this approach weekly over 2 to 3 months. CBT works as well as prescription medicine for many people who have chronic insomnia. It also may provide better long-term relief than medicine alone.                  For people who have insomnia and major depressive disorder, CBT combined with antidepression medicines has shown promise in relieving both conditions.                  Medicines                  Prescription Medicines                  Many prescription medicines are used to treat insomnia. Some are meant for short-term use, while others are meant for longer use.                  Talk to your doctor about the benefits and side effects of insomnia medicines. For example, insomnia medicines can help you fall asleep, but you may feel groggy in the morning after taking them.                  Rare side effects of these medicines include sleep eating, sleep walking, or driving while asleep. If you have side effects from an insomnia medicine, or if it doesn't work well, tell your doctor. He or she might prescribe a different medicine.                  Some insomnia medicines can be habit forming. Ask your doctor about the benefits and risks of insomnia medicines.                  Over-the-Counter Products                  Some over-the-counter (OTC) products claim to treat insomnia. These products include melatonin, L-tryptophan supplements, and valerian teas or extracts.                  The Food and Drug Administration doesn't regulate \u201cnatural\u201d products and some food supplements. Thus, the dose and purity of these substances can vary. How well these products work and how safe they are isn't well understood.                  Some OTC products that contain antihistamines are sold as sleep aids. Although these products might make you sleepy, talk to your doctor before taking them.                  Antihistamines pose risks for some people. Also, these products may not offer the best treatment for your insomnia. Your doctor can advise you whether these products will benefit you."}, {"subject": "You know Diabetes Insipidus?", "Question": "I was born with Diabetes Insipidus and have many problems since the cell was removed when I was 22 and ALL", "focus": "diabetes insipidus", "type": "information", "Answer": "Diabetes insipidus is an uncommon condition in which the kidneys are unable to prevent the excretion of water."}, {"subject": "Anal Fissure", "Question": "I may have a couple anal fissures and looking to speak with someone to get some information and support.", "focus": "anal fissures", "type": "information", "Answer": "An anal fissure is a small split or tear in the thin moist tissue (mucosa) lining the lower rectum (anus)."}, {"subject": "ClinicalTrials.gov - Question - general information", "Question": "Hello, my dad, 68 years old, has gastritis,  it did ache occasionally over the last several years. The other day, he went to hospital to have medical check-up with endoscopic ultrasonography, and found GIST with about 1cm in size. Doctor told him that he may consider surgery or not, it is up to him. What are we supposed to do? will it develop to bad condition? any suggestions?  I 'm looking forward to your early reply. Thank you so much.", "focus": "gist", "type": "information", "Answer": "A gastrointestinal stromal tumor (GIST) is a type of tumor that occurs in the gastrointestinal tract, most commonly in the stomach or small intestine. The tumors are thought to grow from specialized cells found in the gastrointestinal tract called interstitial cells of Cajal (ICCs) or precursors to these cells. GISTs are usually found in adults between ages 40 and 70; rarely, children and young adults develop these tumors. The tumors can be cancerous (malignant) or noncancerous (benign).  Small tumors may cause no signs or symptoms. However, some people with GISTs may experience pain or swelling in the abdomen, nausea, vomiting, loss of appetite, or weight loss. Sometimes, tumors cause bleeding, which may lead to low red blood cell counts (anemia) and, consequently, weakness and tiredness. Bleeding into the intestinal tract may cause black and tarry stools, and bleeding into the throat or stomach may cause vomiting of blood.  Affected individuals with no family history of GIST typically have only one tumor (called a sporadic GIST). People with a family history of GISTs (called familial GISTs) often have multiple tumors and additional signs or symptoms, including noncancerous overgrowth (hyperplasia) of other cells in the gastrointestinal tract and patches of dark skin on various areas of the body. Some affected individuals have a skin condition called urticaria pigmentosa (also known as cutaneous mastocytosis), which is characterized by raised patches of brownish skin that sting or itch when touched."}, {"subject": "Help for my diagnose", "Question": "I have been diagnosed with SCA3. I was wondering if MedlinePlus is able to help me with resources that I may need on my journey through this disease? If not, can you help me find an organization or association that can help me.", "focus": "sca3", "type": "information", "Answer": "Spinocerebellar ataxia type 3 (SCA3) is a condition characterized by progressive problems with movement. People with this condition initially experience problems with coordination and balance (ataxia). Other early signs and symptoms of SCA3 include speech difficulties, uncontrolled muscle tensing (dystonia), muscle stiffness (spasticity), rigidity, tremors, bulging eyes, and double vision. People with this condition may experience sleep disorders such as restless leg syndrome or REM sleep behavior disorder. Restless leg syndrome is a condition characterized by numbness or tingling in the legs accompanied by an urge to move the legs to stop the sensations. REM sleep behavior disorder is a condition in which the muscles are active during the dream (REM) stage of sleep, so an affected person often acts out his or her dreams. These sleep disorders tend to leave affected individuals feeling tired during the day.  Over time, individuals with SCA3 may develop loss of sensation and weakness in the limbs (peripheral neuropathy), muscle cramps, muscle twitches (fasciculations), and swallowing difficulties. Individuals with SCA3 may have problems with memory, planning, and problem solving.  Signs and symptoms of the disorder typically begin in mid-adulthood but can appear anytime from childhood to late adulthood. People with SCA3 eventually require wheelchair assistance. They usually survive 10 to 20 years after symptoms first appear."}, {"subject": "ClinicalTrials.gov - Question - general information", "Question": "how do I get help with my migraines a have bad cluster migraines.", "focus": "migraines", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "There is no specific cure for migraine headaches. The goal is to treat your migraine symptoms right away, and to prevent symptoms by avoiding or changing your triggers.   A key step is learning how to manage your migraines at home. A headache diary can help you identify your headache triggers. Then you and your doctor can plan how to avoid these triggers.  If you have frequent migraines, your doctor may prescribe medicine to reduce the number of attacks. You need to take the medicine every day for it to be effective. Medicines may include:  - Antidepressants  - Blood pressure medicines  - Seizure medicines    Botulinum toxin type A (Botox) injections may also help reduce migraine attacks if they occur more than 15 days a month.  Some people find relief with minerals and vitamins. Check with your doctor to see if riboflavin or magnesium are right for you.  TREATING AN ATTACK  Other medicines are taken at the first sign of a migraine attack. Over-the-counter (OTC) pain medicines, such as acetaminophen, ibuprofen, or aspirin are often helpful when your migraine is mild. Be aware that:   - Taking medicines more than 3 days a week may lead to rebound headaches. These are headaches that keep coming back due to overuse of pain medicine.  - Taking too much acetaminophen can damage your liver.  - Too much ibuprofen or aspirin can irritate your stomach or kidneys.    If these treatments do not help, ask your doctor about prescription medicines. These include nasal sprays, suppositories, or injections.   Some migraine medicines narrow the blood vessels. If you are at risk for having a heart attack or have heart disease, talk with your doctor before using these medicines. Some migraine medicines should not be used by pregnant women. Talk with your doctor about which medicine is right for you if you are pregnant or planning to become pregnant.  Other medicines treat symptoms of migraine, such as nausea and vomiting. They may be used alone or along with the other drugs that treat the migraine itself.   Feverfew is a herb for migraines. It can be effective for some people. Before using feverfew, make sure your doctor approves. Herbal remedies sold in drugstores and health food stores are not regulated. Work with a trained herbalist when selecting herbs."}, {"subject": "know more of Congenital Heart Disease", "Question": "know more of Congenital Heart Disease", "focus": "congenital heart disease", "type": "information", "Answer": "Congenital heart disease\u00a0is a problem with the heart's structure and function that is present at birth."}, {"subject": "Osteoarthritis", "Question": "Are there any researches indicating how early an individual may experience any signs or symptoms of Rheumatoid Arthritis?", "focus": "rheumatoid arthritis", "type": "symptom", "Answer": "Most of the time, RA affects joints on both sides of the body equally. Wrists, fingers, knees, feet, and ankles are the most commonly affected.  The disease often begins slowly. Early symptoms may include minor joint pain, stiffness, and fatigue.   Joint symptoms may include:  - Morning stiffness, which lasts more than 1 hour, is common. Joints may feel warm, tender, and stiff when not used for an hour.  - Joint pain is often felt on the same joint on both sides of the body.  - Over time, joints may lose their range of motion and may become deformed.     Other symptoms include:  - Chest pain when taking a breath (pleurisy)  - Dry eyes and mouth (Sjogren syndrome)  - Eye burning, itching, and discharge  - Nodules under the skin (usually a sign of more severe disease)  - Numbness, tingling, or burning in the hands and feet  - Sleep difficulties"}, {"subject": null, "Question": "Genetic testing.  My mother in law is in the last stage if lung cancer and only has days to live.  My question is...testing her and comparing her tests with my husbands and his sisters test help to determine if it is genetic?  My mother in law ([NAME]) and her mother and her mithers sister both had lung cancer and none if them were smokers.  I'm real worried about my husband getting lung cancer now and I want find out what we can do to protect him.Thank you,[NAME] ", "focus": "lung cancer", "type": "prevention", "Answer": "If you smoke, now is the time to quit. If you are having trouble quitting, talk with your doctor. There are many methods to help you quit, from support groups to prescription medicines. Also, try to avoid secondhand smoke."}, {"subject": "oleander poisoning", "Question": "If oleandor was ingested by touching the plant stems inner part and then directly eating without washing hands, how long would u exspect symptoms would start? And how severe would you say symptoms may get.", "focus": "oleander poisoning", "type": "symptom", "Answer": "Eyes, ears, nose, mouth, and throat:  - Blurred vision  - Vision disturbances, including halos   Gastrointestinal:   - Diarrhea  - Loss of appetite   - Nausea  - Stomach pain  - Vomiting   Heart and blood:   - Irregular or slow heartbeat  - Low blood pressure  - Weakness   Nervous system:   - Confusion  - Death  - Depression   - Disorientation  - Dizziness  - Drowsiness  - Fainting  - Headache  - Lethargy   Skin:   - Hives  - Rash   Note: Depression, loss of appetite, and halos are usually only seen in chronic overdose cases."}, {"subject": "I have no help its about 4 years now I have ingrown toenail", "Question": "i have a problem of ingrown toenail its about 4 years now I have this problem i need help", "focus": "ingrown toenail", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "If you have diabetes, nerve damage in the leg or foot, poor blood circulation to your foot, or an infection around the nail, go to the doctor right away. Do\u00a0not try to treat\u00a0an ingrown nail\u00a0at home.  Otherwise, to treat an ingrown nail at home:  - Soak the foot in warm water 3 to 4 times a day if possible. After soaking, keep the toe dry.  - Gently massage over the inflamed skin.  - Place a small piece of cotton or dental floss under the nail. Wet the cotton with water or antiseptic.   When trimming your toenails:  - Briefly soak your foot in warm water to soften the nail.  - Use a clean, sharp trimmer.  - Trim toenails straight across the top. Do not taper or round the corners or trim too short. Do not try to cut out the ingrown portion of the nail yourself. This will only make the problem worse.   Consider wearing sandals until the problem\u00a0goes away. Over-the-counter medicine that is applied to the ingrown toenail may help with the pain, but it\u00a0does not treat the problem.  If this does not work and the ingrown nail gets worse, see your family doctor, a foot specialist (podiatrist) or a skin specialist (dermatologist).  If your ingrown nail does not heal or keeps coming back, your doctor may remove part of the nail:  - Numbing medicine is first injected into the toe.  - The doctor uses\u00a0scissors to cut along the edge of the nail where the skin is growing over. This portion of the nail is removed. This procedure is called a partial nail avulsion.  - It takes 2 to 4 months for the nail to regrow.   Sometimes your doctor will use a chemical, electrical current, or another small surgical cut to destroy or remove the area from which a new nail may grow.  If the toe is infected, your doctor may prescribe antibiotics."}, {"subject": "ClinicalTrials.gov - General Complaint", "Question": "Dear sir/ madam. I am a patient suffering from Friedreich's ataxia and i heard there was a medicine for it. In 2009 and since we are looking for the medicine kindly help on this and I have DNA report could You please help us on this as there are two people respective age 22 years and 24 years suffering from it. Looking for your help on this ASAP and please let us know when the medicine will be there in market and attaching two files for your reference", "focus": "friedreich's ataxia", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Treatment for Friedreich ataxia includes:  - Counseling  - Speech therapy  - Physical therapy  - Walking aids or wheelchairs    Orthopedic devices (braces) may be needed for scoliosis and foot problems. Treating heart disease and diabetes help people live longer and improve their quality of life."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "article defining 'conversion disorder' In your article defining 'conversion disorder', [http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/ency/article/000954.htm] , the quote \"Conversion disorder is a mental health condition in which a person has blindness paralysis, or other nervous system (neurologic) symptoms that cannot be explained be medical evaluation\" , seemed to imply that the physical symptoms were valid as proving to be valid, but however the doctor could not 'figure' out why,.....but when I went to another source, another article quotes the disorder as a \"physical disability that is not caused by any physical impairment\" -so I am defining this as symptoms that are visibly correct as analyzed visually but when under examination for deadened nerves or broken bones, no evidence is found? >that is the definition I am getting from the other source about this disorder. For example, someone claims blindness, as my instructor explained, and when the person claiming blindness is placed near a ledge , does not walk off the ledge.....since I am assuming also that optical tests of the retina, or pupil proved nothing substantial?  ", "focus": "conversion disorder", "type": "diagnosis", "Answer": "Diagnostic testing does not find any physical cause for the symptoms.  The doctor will do a physical exam and may order diagnostic tests. These are to make sure there are no physical causes for the symptom."}, {"subject": "spg11", "Question": "My 24 year old son was recently diagnosed with  spg11 after over 15 years of trying to figure out what was wrong.  We are already doing some of the common treatments.  My question is, where do we go from here to give him the best chance at life,", "focus": "spg11", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "These resources address the diagnosis or management of spastic paraplegia type 11:  - Gene Review: Gene Review: Spastic Paraplegia 11  - Genetic Testing Registry: Spastic paraplegia 11, autosomal recessive  - Spastic Paraplegia Foundation, Inc.: Treatments and Therapies   These resources from MedlinePlus offer information about the diagnosis and management of various health conditions:  - Diagnostic Tests  - Drug Therapy  - Surgery and Rehabilitation  - Genetic Counseling   - Palliative Care"}, {"subject": null, "Question": "I have been battling Anal fissure for close to two years now and it has refused to heal all these while. Please what do you suggest i do?  Thanks", "focus": "anal fissure", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Most fissures heal on their own and do not need treatment.  To prevent or treat anal fissures in infants, be sure to change diapers often and clean the area gently.  CHILDREN AND ADULTS  Worrying about pain during a bowel movement may cause a person to avoid them. But not having bowel movements will only cause the stools to become even harder, which can make anal fissure worse.  Prevent hard stools and constipation by:  - Making dietary changes -- eating more fiber or bulk, such as fruits, vegetables, and grains  - Drinking more fluids  - Using stool softeners    Applying the following ointments or creams to the area may soothe the skin:  - Numbing cream, if pain interferes with normal bowel movements  - Petroleum jelly  - Zinc oxide, 1% hydrocortisone cream, Preparation H, and other products    A sitz bath is a warm water bath used for healing or cleansing. You should sit in the bath two to three times a day. The water should cover only your hips and buttocks.  If the anal fissures do not go away with home care methods, treatment may involve:  - Botox injections into the muscle in the anus (anal sphincter)  - Minor surgery to relax the anal muscle  - Prescription creams such as nitrates or calcium channel blockers, applied over the fissure to help relax the muscles"}, {"subject": "menkes syndrome /kinky hair syndrome", "Question": "My daughter has menkes syndrome and would like to know how to go about. Thx", "focus": "menkes syndrome", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Treatment usually only helps when started very early in the course of the disease. Injections of copper into a vein or under the skin have been used with mixed results."}, {"subject": "Nephrotic Syndrome", "Question": "What is Nephrotic Syndrome.  What are its causes and cures?", "focus": "nephrotic syndrome", "type": "information", "Answer": "Nephrotic syndrome is a group of symptoms that include protein in the urine, low blood protein levels in the blood, high cholesterol levels, high triglyceride levels, and swelling."}, {"subject": "GENDER DYSPHORIA", "Question": "NO HEALTH CARE ON MY SON SUFFERING FROM GENDER DYSPHORIA WHAT CAN WE DO TO HELP HIM HE WORKED OUT OF HIGH SCHOOL NO PROBLEMS NOW NOT WORKING AND SHUTTING HIMSELF IN HIS ROOM 24/7 THERES NOTHING ABOUT THIS CONDITION IN OUR AREA WE LIVE IN [LOCATION]. NO HELP IN AREA WHAT CAN WE DO HE HAS HAD BAD THOUGHTS ALREADY PLEASE HELP US WITH SOME SORT OF INFO THANK YUO [NAME] [LOCATION] [CONTACT]", "focus": "gender dysphoria", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Individual and family therapy is recommended for children to create a supportive environment at home and in school. Individual and, if appropriate, couples therapy is recommended for adults.   Sex reassignment through surgery and hormonal therapy is an option. But identity problems may continue after this treatment."}, {"subject": "Bowel Ischemia", "Question": "My mother recently died from Bowel Ischemia and Septic Shock.  My question is this, she was in the ER for 12 hours before she was even seen by the general surgeon and then he wasn't convinced that it was this condition yet.  He said that he'd check on her in the morning once she was finally put into an ICU room (this was at 11 p.m.).  I last spoke to her at midnight that evening and that was the last time that she was conscious.  By the time she got to the ICU just 2-3 hours later, she was unresponsive and put on life support.  Surgery was eventually performed later that afternoon and 90% of her small intestine had to be removed.  She died early the next evening.  My question to you is did they wait too long to do anything for her?  Could she have been saved if surgery had been done sooner?  I'm possibly thinking of bringing on a lawsuit.....Please advise with any answers to my questions that you can give.  Thank you!", "focus": "septic shock", "type": "prognosis", "Answer": "Septic shock has a high death rate. The death rate depends on the patient's age and overall health, the cause of the infection, how many organs have failed, and how quickly and aggressively medical therapy is started."}, {"subject": "Cushing, fybromyaglia, Chronic fatigue", "Question": "my main concern is no treatment and the musclar distrophy effecting my heart, legs feet, shoulders, arms, etc.", "focus": "cushing", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Treatment depends on the cause.  Cushing syndrome caused by corticosteroid use:  - Your doctor will instruct you to slowly decrease the medicine dosage. Stopping the medicine suddenly can be dangerous.  - If you cannot stop taking the medicine because of disease, your high blood sugar, high cholesterol levels, and bone thinning or osteoporosis should be closely monitored.    With Cushing syndrome caused by a pituitary or a tumor that releases ACTH (Cushing disease), you may need:  - Surgery to remove the tumor.  - Radiation after removal of a pituitary tumor in some cases.  - Cortisol replacement therapy after surgery and possibly for the rest of your life.    With Cushing syndrome due to an adrenal tumor\u00a0or other tumors:  - You may need surgery to remove the tumor.  - If the tumor cannot be removed, you may need medicines to help block the release of cortisol."}, {"subject": "tick bites", "Question": "my husband was diagnosed with Rocky Mountain Spotted fever about 6 1/2 years ago.  Then about 1 1/2 years ago he was diagnosed with Lyme Disease.  With him having had both what damage if any to his body could possibly happen.  He has had alot of medical problems since.  Now has been diagnosed with type II diabetes.", "focus": "rocky mountain spotted fever", "type": "prognosis", "Answer": "Treatment usually cures the infection. About 3% of people who get this disease will die."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "Please help me.  have the honor to write to YOU. and I heard about your humanity and my hope in you a great And ask you for help I need you and I Will Be very very grateful to you. I am 30 years [NAME] state of Algeria , Batna. I suffer from a disease of chronic renal failure, dialysis was carried out 10 years ago. (Dialysis 3 times / week) continuous arteriovenous fistulas and the surgery (4till now). I live a hard life with illness and suffering continues to require a kidney transplant in order to get rid of this suffering Because the process of kidney transplantation in Algeria is slow and very rare, especially those without a family donor like me. Almost no hope for them. Please help me great hope in you (I'm sorry for writing bad because I do not know English we ", "focus": "chronic renal failure", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Controlling blood pressure will slow further kidney damage. Angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors or angiotensin receptor blockers (ARBs) are used most often. The goal is to keep blood pressure at or below 130/80 mm Hg. Making lifestyle changes can help protect the kidneys, and prevent heart disease and stroke, such as: DO NOT smoke.\nEat meals that are low in fat and cholesterol. Get regular exercise (talk to your doctor or nurse before starting to exercise). Take drugs to lower your cholesterol, if needed. Keep your blood sugar under control. Avoid eating too much salt or potassium. Always talk to your kidney specialist before taking any over-the-counter medicine. This includes vitamins, herbs and supplements. Make sure all of the providers you visit know you have CKD. Other treatments may include: Medicines called phosphate binders, to help prevent high phosphorous levels Extra iron in the diet, iron pills, iron given through a vein (intravenous iron) special shots of a medicine called erythropoietin, and blood transfusions to treat anemia Extra calcium and vitamin D (always talk to your provider before taking) Your provider may have you follow a special diet for CKD. Limiting fluids Eating less protein Restricting salt, potassium, phosphorous, and other electrolytes Getting enough calories to prevent weight loss All people with CKD should be up-to-date on the following vaccinations: Hepatitis A vaccine Hepatitis B vaccine Flu vaccine Pneumonia vaccine (PPV)"}, {"subject": "ClinicalTrials.gov - Question - general information", "Question": "My cousin she is leber amaurosis she need help I don't know where to start from", "focus": "leber amaurosis", "type": "information", "Answer": "Leber congenital amaurosis is an eye disorder that primarily affects the retina, which is the specialized tissue at the back of the eye that detects light and color. People with this disorder typically have severe visual impairment beginning in infancy. The visual impairment tends to be stable, although it may worsen very slowly over time.  Leber congenital amaurosis is also associated with other vision problems, including an increased sensitivity to light (photophobia), involuntary movements of the eyes (nystagmus), and extreme farsightedness (hyperopia). The pupils, which usually expand and contract in response to the amount of light entering the eye, do not react normally to light. Instead, they expand and contract more slowly than normal, or they may not respond to light at all. Additionally, the clear front covering of the eye (the cornea) may be cone-shaped and abnormally thin, a condition known as keratoconus.  A specific behavior called Franceschetti's oculo-digital sign is characteristic of Leber congenital amaurosis. This sign consists of poking, pressing, and rubbing the eyes with a knuckle or finger. Researchers suspect that this behavior may contribute to deep-set eyes and keratoconus in affected children.  In rare cases, delayed development and intellectual disability have been reported in people with the features of Leber congenital amaurosis. However, researchers are uncertain whether these individuals actually have Leber congenital amaurosis or another syndrome with similar signs and symptoms.  At least 13 types of Leber congenital amaurosis have been described. The types are distinguished by their genetic cause, patterns of vision loss, and related eye abnormalities."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "My father is having cardiomyopathy through genes. He is 83 now. He was absoulutely normal till now. recently he is getting breathlessness. and he was admitted to the hospital twice. The doctors are telling that multi dieases are attacking his heart. I just want to know exactly what is happening and what precautions that he should take in future. What are the chances of survival? Please help. ", "focus": "cardiomyopathy", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "When possible, the cause of cardiomyopathy is treated. Medicines and lifestyle changes are often needed to treat the symptoms of heart failure, angina, and abnormal heart rhythms.  Procedures or surgeries may also be used, including:  - A defibrillator that sends an electrical pulse to stop life-threatening abnormal heart rhythms  - A pacemaker that treats a slow heart rate or helps both sides of the heart beat at the same time  - Coronary artery bypass (CABG) surgery or angioplasty\u00a0that may\u00a0improve blood flow to the damaged or weakened heart muscle  - Heart transplant that may be tried when all other treatments have failed    Recently, implantable artificial heart pumps have been developed. These may be used for very severe cases. However, not all patients need or are able to have this advanced treatment."}, {"subject": "Questions on albinism", "Question": "Hello my name is [NAME] and I'm hoping you can help me. When i was born my doctor diagnosed me with albinism. I have color in my hair (brown) and in my eyes (hazel) they do not shake. My skin is fair but my markings are visible. It is not one solid fair white on all of me. I apparently have 3 different levels. most of my body is covered by level 1 pigmentation (the fairest) i have level 2 on some as well and a small patch of my arm of level (3) it basically looks like a huge birthmark that goes from my right side of the body to the left.  When I was born the doctors still didn't know much about Albinism and I\"m hoping to learn more myself. For instance what type this would fall under... I hope you can help.", "focus": "albinism", "type": "information", "Answer": "Albinism is a defect of melanin production that results in little or no color (pigment) in the skin, hair, and eyes."}, {"subject": "typhoid fever", "Question": "Hi, My name is [NAME] from india i have suffering from typhoid please give me solution  i have one question i had got treatment from one year but i am not well now give me solution?", "focus": "typhoid", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Fluids and electrolytes may be given by IV (into a vein) or you may be asked to drink water with electrolyte packets.  Antibiotics are given to kill the bacteria. There are increasing rates of antibiotic resistance throughout the world, so your health care provider will check current recommendations before choosing an antibiotic."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "GERD.  I'm a 72 year old female, and have diverticulosis,gastritis, and esophagitis.  I tried to see three different doctors today, but all were booked.  I honestly don't know what to do.  It hurts in my chest, and I can hardly talk. ", "focus": "gerd", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "You can make many lifestyle changes to help treat your symptoms.  Other tips include:  - If you are overweight or obese, in many cases, losing weight can help.  - Avoid drugs such as aspirin, ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin), or naproxen (Aleve, Naprosyn). Take acetaminophen (Tylenol) to relieve pain.  - Take all of your medicines with plenty of water. When your doctor gives you a new medicine, ask whether it will make your heartburn worse.    You may use over-the-counter antacids after meals and at bedtime, although the relief may not last very long. Common side effects of antacids include diarrhea or constipation.  Other over-the-counter and prescription drugs can treat GERD. They work more slowly than antacids, but give you longer relief. Your pharmacist, doctor, or nurse can tell you how to take these drugs.  - Proton pump inhibitors (PPIs) decrease the amount of acid produced in your stomach  - H2 blockers also lower the amount of acid released in the stomach    Anti-reflux surgery may be an option for people whose symptoms do not go away with lifestyle changes and medicines. Heartburn and other symptoms should improve after surgery. But you may still need to take drugs for your heartburn.  There are also new therapies for reflux that can be performed through an endoscope (a flexible tube passed through the mouth into the stomach)."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "Tests for Haemophilia. Hi, I was wondering if blood clotting assays are always positive if one has mild-moderate hemophilia and what the name is of the genetic tests for hemophilia? I have a history of internal spontaneous bleeding into the joints or with eating garlic or onions (in large amounts).I also hemmorhage after injuries (arm injury, head injury hemmorhage, and pregnancy birth hemmorhage--both times).  I've had to have blood transfusions and shots to control the bleeding but it's usually possible to control it. I believe I may have passed this on to my son as he was determined by a doctor to be a heavy bleeder at circumcision. While on the [LOCATION]t, I was asked by a [LOCATION] if anyone had done a work-up on me for hemophilia or any clotting disorder and I said not to my knowledge.  I asked if they were going to do it and she said to follow up with a primary doctor for it.  She also said it could be expensive. This is why I'm asking, if I go to a medical appointment as a private-pay patient, and want to have testing done, which tests would you recommend? [NAME] ", "focus": "hemophilia", "type": "diagnosis", "Answer": "Most often, hemophilia is diagnosed after a person has an abnormal bleeding episode. It can also be diagnosed by a blood test done to detect the problem, if other family members have the condition."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "I am 23yr boy,i have knock knees i want treatment. Please help me.", "focus": "knock knees", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Knock knees are not treated in most cases.  If the problem continues after age 7, the child may use a night brace. This brace is attached to a shoe.   Surgery may be considered for knock knees that are severe and continue beyond late childhood."}, {"subject": "Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease", "Question": "Can GERD BE CURED? I AM SUFFERING FROM THIS DISEASE FOR ALMOST THREE YEARS NOW.I HAVE GONE TO MANY HOSPITALS  BUT STILL CAN'T BE CURED.I HAVE BEEN GIVEN OMEPRAZOLE CAPSULES MANY TIMES.PLEASE HELP ME.", "focus": "gerd", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "You can make many lifestyle changes to help treat your symptoms.  Other tips include:  - If you are overweight or obese, in many cases, losing weight can help.  - Avoid drugs such as aspirin, ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin), or naproxen (Aleve, Naprosyn). Take acetaminophen (Tylenol) to relieve pain.  - Take all of your medicines with plenty of water. When your doctor gives you a new medicine, ask whether it will make your heartburn worse.    You may use over-the-counter antacids after meals and at bedtime, although the relief may not last very long. Common side effects of antacids include diarrhea or constipation.  Other over-the-counter and prescription drugs can treat GERD. They work more slowly than antacids, but give you longer relief. Your pharmacist, doctor, or nurse can tell you how to take these drugs.  - Proton pump inhibitors (PPIs) decrease the amount of acid produced in your stomach  - H2 blockers also lower the amount of acid released in the stomach    Anti-reflux surgery may be an option for people whose symptoms do not go away with lifestyle changes and medicines. Heartburn and other symptoms should improve after surgery. But you may still need to take drugs for your heartburn.  There are also new therapies for reflux that can be performed through an endoscope (a flexible tube passed through the mouth into the stomach)."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "diagnosis of OI/ resources. I was writing to inquire about more information regarding the diagnosis of OI.  We have family members who are in the process of waiting for genetic testing to come back but are under allegations of child abuse.  Is there any information and / or resources that may be helpful to us? Any help is appreciated. Thank you,[NAME] ", "focus": "oi", "type": "diagnosis", "Answer": "OI is most often suspected in children whose bones break with very little force. A physical exam may show that the whites of their eyes have a blue tint.  A definitive diagnosis may be made using a skin punch biopsy. Family members may be given a DNA blood test.  If there is a family history of OI, chorionic villus sampling  may be done during pregnancy to determine if the baby has the condition. However, because so many different mutations can cause OI, some forms cannot be diagnosed with a genetic test.  The severe form of type II OI can be seen on ultrasound when the fetus is as young as 16 weeks."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "atypical pnuemonia.  what is the possibility of atypical pneumonia occurring again less than a month after treatment? ", "focus": "atypical pneumonia", "type": "prognosis", "Answer": "Most patients with pneumonia due to mycoplasma or chlamydophila get better with the right antibiotics. Legionella pneumonia can be severe. It can lead to problems, especially in patients with kidney failure, diabetes, COPD, or a weak immune system. It can also lead to death."}, {"subject": null, "Question": "Can u please send stuff on fibromyalgia as well ", "focus": "fibromyalgia", "type": "information", "Answer": "Fibromyalgia is a common syndrome in which a person has long-term pain, spread throughout the body. The pain is most often linked to fatigue, sleep problems, headaches, depression, and anxiety.  People with fibromalgia may also have tenderness in the joints, muscles, tendons, and other soft tissues."}, {"subject": "genital warts on penis", "Question": "i have taken two treatment of this but still i have small warts please tell me which is the best madcine or cream", "focus": "warts", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "Your health care provider can treat a wart if you do not like how it looks or if it is painful.  Do NOT attempt to remove a wart yourself by burning, cutting, tearing, picking, or by any other method.  MEDICINES  Over-the-counter medicines are available to remove warts.   Do NOT use over-the-counter wart medicines on your face or genitals. Warts in these areas need to be treated by a health care provider.  To use wart-removal medicine:  - File the wart with a nail file or emery board when your skin is damp (for example, after a shower or bath). This helps remove dead tissue. Do not use the same emery board on your nails.  - Put the medicine on the wart every day for several weeks or months. Follow the instructions on the label.  - Cover the wart with a bandage to prevent it from spreading.\u00a0    OTHER TREATMENTS  Special foot cushions can help ease the pain from plantar warts. You can buy these at drugstores without a prescription. Use socks. Wear shoes with plenty of room. Avoid high heels.  Your health care provider may need to trim away thick skin or calluses that form over warts on your foot or around nails.   Your provider may recommend the following treatments if your warts do not go away:  - Stronger (prescription) medicines  - A blistering solution   - Freezing the wart (cryotherapy) to remove it  - Burning the wart (electrocautery) to remove it  - Laser treatment for difficult to remove warts  - Immunotherapy, which gives you a shot of a substance that causes an allergic reaction and helps the wart go away  - Skin medicine called imiquimod    Genital warts are treated in a different way than most other warts.  A medicine called veregen may be used on genital warts, as well as on other warts."}, {"subject": "X-linked congenital stationary night blindness", "Question": "i m suffering from similar or same decease.my mothers father suffered from same & my brother also.we have problem in low light infact cant view in damp conditions during day also have myopia but still not normal myopia cant see little object with clarity.life is looking like imprisonment.is there any chance for our recovery from this x linked decease.will we be able to see like normal ones.plz help. my age 38 y brother 44.address [LOCATION]", "focus": "x-linked congenital stationary night blindness", "type": "treatment", "Answer": "These resources address the diagnosis or management of X-linked congenital stationary night blindness:  - American Optometric Association: Infant Vision  - Gene Review: Gene Review: X-Linked Congenital Stationary Night Blindness  - Genetic Testing Registry: Congenital stationary night blindness  - Genetic Testing Registry: Congenital stationary night blindness, type 1A  - Genetic Testing Registry: Congenital stationary night blindness, type 2A  - MedlinePlus Encyclopedia: Electroretinography  - MedlinePlus Encyclopedia: Eye movements - Uncontrollable  - MedlinePlus Encyclopedia: Nearsightedness  - MedlinePlus Encyclopedia: Strabismus  - MedlinePlus Encyclopedia: Vision - Night Blindness   These resources from MedlinePlus offer information about the diagnosis and management of various health conditions:  - Diagnostic Tests  - Drug Therapy  - Surgery and Rehabilitation  - Genetic Counseling   - Palliative Care"}, {"subject": null, "Question": "How bad can endometriosis get?", "focus": "endometriosis", "type": "prognosis", "Answer": "Hormone therapy and laparoscopy cannot cure endometriosis. However, in some women, these treatments may help relieve symptoms for years.  Removal of the uterus, fallopian tubes, and both ovaries (a hysterectomy) gives you the best chance for a cure."}, {"subject": "Gastroparesis", "Question": "I am a current Gastroparesis fighter with a GJ feeding tube. I am also one of the admins for a GP support group and an advocacy group. I have become a volunteer advocater. I would appreciate any info you can share about Gastroparesis, Feeding tubes, and even TPN. Thanks", "focus": "gastroparesis", "type": "information", "Answer": "Gastroparesis is a condition that reduces the ability of the stomach to empty its contents. It does not involve a blockage (obstruction)."}]